<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<verses>
	<verse from="Matthew 11:28-30" version="NAS">"Come to Me, all who are weary and heavy-laden, and I will give you rest. "Take My yoke upon you and learn from Me, for I am gentle and humble in heart, and You will find rest for your souls. "For My yoke is easy and My burden is light."</verse>
	<verse from="Proverbs 3:5-6" version="NAS">Trust in the LORD with all your heart And do not lean on your own understanding. In all your ways acknowledge Him, And He will make your paths straight.</verse>
	<verse from="2 Corinthians 9:8" version="NAS">And God is able to make all grace abound to you, so that always having all sufficiency in everything, you may have an abundance for every good deed;</verse>
	<verse from="Romans 8:28" version="NAS">And we know that God causes all things to work together for good to those who love God, to those who are called R393 according to His purpose.</verse>
	<verse from="Nehemiah 8:10" version="NAS">Do not be grieved, for the joy of the LORD is your strength.</verse>
	<verse from="2 Corinthians 12:9" version="NAS">And He has said to me, "My grace is sufficient for you, for power is perfected in weakness." </verse>
	<verse from="Ezra 8:22" version="NAS">The hand of our God is favorably disposed to all those who seek Him, but His power and His anger are against all those who forsake Him. </verse>
	<verse from="Nahum 1:7" version="NAS">The LORD is good, A stronghold in the day of trouble, And He knows those who take refuge in Him. </verse>
	<verse from="Micah 6:8" version="NAS">He has told you, O man, what is good; And what does the LORD require of you But to do justice, to love kindness, And to walk humbly with your God?</verse>
	<verse from="John 11:25" version="NAS">I am the resurrection and the life; he who believes in Me will live even if he dies, and everyone who lives and believes in Me will never die.</verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 46:1" version="NAS">God is our refuge and strength, A very present help in trouble.</verse>
	<verse from="Luke 4:5" version="KJ">Man shall not live by bread alone, but by every word of God.</verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 37:3-4" version="NAS">Trust in the LORD and do good; Dwell in the land and cultivate faithfulness. Delight yourself in the LORD ; And He will give you the desires of your heart.</verse>
	<verse from="Philippians 4:7" version="NAS">And the peace of God, which surpasses all comprehension, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus.</verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 16:11" version="NAS">You will make known to me the path of life; In Your presence is fullness of joy; In Your right hand there are pleasures forever.</verse>
	<verse from="Philippians 4:12-13" version="NAS">I know how to get along with humble means, and I also know how to live in prosperity; in any and every circumstance I have learned the secret of being filled and going hungry, both of having abundance and suffering need. I can do all things through Him who strengthens me.</verse>
	<verse from="Matthew 5:8" version="NAS">Blessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see God.</verse>
	<verse from="Proverbs 8:34-35" version="NAS">Blessed is the man who listens to me, Watching daily at my gates, Waiting at my doorposts. "For he who finds me finds life And obtains favor from the LORD.</verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 1:1-2" version="NAS">How blessed is the man who does not walk in the counsel of the wicked, Nor stand in the path of sinners, Nor sit in the seat of scoffers! But his delight is in the law of the LORD, And in His law he meditates day and night.</verse>
	<verse from="Colossians 3:17" version="NAS">Whatever you do in word or deed, do all in the name of the Lord Jesus, giving thanks through Him to God the Father.</verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 103:2-3" version="NAS">Bless the LORD, O my soul, And forget none of His benefits; Who pardons all your iniquities, Who heals all your diseases;</verse>
	<verse from="Isaiah 10:23" version="NAS">For a complete destruction, one that is decreed, the Lord GOD of hosts will execute in the midst of the whole land.</verse>
	<verse from="John 8:12" version="NAS">I am the Light of the world; he who follows Me will not walk in the darkness, but will have the Light of life.</verse>
	<verse from="Isaiah 12:2" version="NAS">"Behold, God is my salvation, I will trust and not be afraid; For the LORD GOD is my strength and song, And He has become my salvation." </verse>
	<verse from="1 John 3:23" version="NAS">This is His commandment, that we believe in the name of His Son Jesus Christ, and love one another, just as He commanded us.</verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 33:12" version="NAS">Blessed is the nation whose God is the LORD, The people whom He has chosen for His own inheritance.</verse>
	<verse from="1 John 3:18" version="NAS">Little children, let us not love with word or with tongue, but in deed and truth.</verse>
	<verse from="Philippians 1:20" version="NAS">according to my earnest expectation and hope, that I will not be put to shame in anything, but that with all boldness, Christ will even now, as always, be exalted in my body, whether by life or by death.</verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 55:22" version="NAS">Cast your burden upon the LORD and He will sustain you; He will never allow the righteous to be shaken.</verse>
	<verse from="Isaiah 30:15" version="NAS">In repentance and rest you will be saved, In quietness and trust is your strength.</verse>
	<verse from="2 Chronicles 15:2" version="NAS">The Lord is with you when you are with him. If you seek him, he will be found by you, but if you forsake him, he will forsake you.</verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 25:3" version="NAS">Indeed, none of those who wait for You will be ashamed; Those who deal treacherously without cause will be ashamed.</verse>
	<verse from="1 Peter 1:17" version="NAS">If you address as Father the One who impartially judges according to each one's work, conduct yourselves in fear during the time of your stay on earth;</verse>
	<verse from="Isaiah 26:8" version="NAS">Indeed, while following the way of Your judgments, O LORD, We have waited for You eagerly ; Your name, even Your memory, is the desire of our souls.</verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 139:1-3" version="NAS">O LORD, You have searched me and known me. You know when I sit down and when I rise up; You understand my thought from afar. You scrutinize my path and my lying down, And are intimately acquainted with all my ways.</verse>
	<verse from="Hebrews 4:15-16" version="NAS">For we do not have a high priest who cannot sympathize with our weaknesses, but One who has been tempted in all things as we are, yet without sin. Therefore let us draw near with confidence to the throne of grace, so that we may receive mercy and find grace to help in time of need.</verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 91:1" version="NAS">He who dwells in the shelter of the Most High Will abide in the shadow of the Almighty.</verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 73:25-26" version="NAS">Whom have I in heaven but You? And besides You, I desire nothing on earth. My flesh and my heart may fail, But God is the strength of my heart and my portion forever.</verse>
	<verse from="Isaiah 40:31" version="NAS">Yet those who wait for the LORD Will gain new strength ; They will mount up with wings like eagles, They will run and not get tired, They will walk and not become weary.</verse>
	<verse from="James 1:12" version="NAS">Blessed is a man who perseveres under trial ; for once he has been approved, he will receive the crown of life which the Lord has promised to those who love Him. </verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 2:11" version="NAS">Worship the LORD with reverence And rejoice with trembling.</verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 149:4" version="NAS">For the LORD takes pleasure in His people ; He will beautify the afflicted ones with salvation.</verse>
	<verse from="Isaiah 41:10" version="NAS">'Do not fear, for I am with you; Do not anxiously look about you, for I am your God. I will strengthen you, surely I will help you, Surely I will uphold you with My righteous right hand.'</verse>
	<verse from="Isaiah 40:8" version="NAS">The grass withers, the flower fades, But the word of our God stands forever.</verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 150:1" version="NAS">Praise the LORD ! Praise God in His sanctuary ; Praise Him in His mighty expanse.</verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 147:1" version="NAS">Praise the LORD ! For it is good to sing praises to our God ; For it is pleasant and praise is becoming.</verse>
	<verse from="Isaiah 46:10" version="NAS">Declaring the end from the beginning, And from ancient times things which have not been done, Saying, 'My purpose will be established, And I will accomplish all My good pleasure.'</verse>
	<verse from="Isaiah 54:10" version="NAS">Though the mountains be shaken and the hills be removed, yet my unfailing love for you will not be shaken nor my covenant of peace be removed," says the Lord, who has compassion on you.</verse>
	<verse from="Philippians 2:4" version="NAS">Each of you should look not only to your own interests, but also to the interests of others.</verse>
	<verse from="Philippians 2:3" version="NAS">Do nothing from selfishness or empty conceit, but with humility of mind regard one another as more important than yourselves.</verse>
	<verse from="John 8:51" version="NAS">"Truly, truly, I say to you, if anyone keeps My word he will never see death."</verse>
	<verse from="Proverbs 10:7" version="NAS">The memory of the righteous is blessed, But the name of the wicked will rot.</verse>
	<verse from="Isaiah 51:11" version="NAS">So the ransomed of the LORD will return And come with joyful shouting to Zion, And everlasting joy will be on their heads. They will obtain gladness and joy, And sorrow and sighing will flee away.</verse>
	<verse from="Isaiah 54:10" version="NAS">"For the mountains may be removed and the hills may shake, But My lovingkindness will not be removed from you, And My covenant of peace will not be shaken," Says the LORD who has compassion on you.</verse>
	<verse from="Romans 8:38-39" version="NAS">For I am convinced that neither death, nor life, nor angels, nor principalities, nor things present, nor things to come, nor powers, nor height, nor depth, nor any other created thing, will be able to separate us from the love of God, which is in Christ Jesus our Lord.</verse>
	<verse from="Isaiah 55:6" version="NAS">Seek the LORD while He may be found; Call upon Him while He is near.</verse>
	<verse from="1 John 2:15" version="NAS">Do not love the world nor the things in the world. If anyone loves the world, the love of the Father is not in him.</verse>
	<verse from="Isaiah 57:15" version="NAS">For thus says the high and exalted One Who lives forever, whose name is Holy, "I dwell on a high and holy place, And also with the contrite and lowly of spirit In order to revive the spirit of the lowly And to revive the heart of the contrite.</verse>
	<verse from="Isaiah 61:11" version="NAS">For as the earth brings forth its sprouts, And as a garden causes the things sown in it to spring up, So the Lord GOD will cause righteousness and praise To spring up before all the nations.</verse>
	<verse from="Isaiah 63:16" version="NAS">You, O LORD, are our Father, Our Redeemer from of old is Your name.</verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 30:4-5" version="NAS">Sing praise to the LORD, you His godly ones, And give thanks to His holy name. For His anger is but for a moment, His favor is for a lifetime ; Weeping may last for the night, But a shout of joy comes in the morning.</verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 32:1" version="NAS">How blessed is he whose transgression is forgiven, Whose sin is covered !</verse>
	<verse from="Zechariah 9:9" version="NAS">Rejoice greatly, O daughter of Zion ! Shout in triumph, O daughter of Jerusalem ! Behold, your king is coming to you; He is just and endowed with salvation, Humble, and mounted on a donkey, Even on a colt, the foal of a donkey.</verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 71:20" version="NAS">20.You who have shown me many troubles and distresses Will revive me again, And will bring me up again from the depths of the earth.</verse>
	<verse from="1 John 1:7" version="NAS">but if we walk in the Light as He Himself is in the Light, we have fellowship with one another, and the blood of Jesus His Son cleanses us from all sin.</verse>
	<verse from="1 John 3:4" version="NAS">Everyone who practices sin also practices lawlessness ; and sin is lawlessness.</verse>
	<verse from="1 John 3:24" version="NAS">The one who keeps His commandments abides in Him, and He in him. We know by this that He abides in us, by the Spirit whom He has given us.</verse>
	<verse from="1 John 4:6" version="NAS">We are from God ; he who knows God listens to us; he who is not from God does not listen to us.</verse>
	<verse from="2 John 1:9" version="NAS">Anyone who goes too far and does not abide in the teaching of Christ, does not have God ; the one who abides in the teaching, he has both the Father and the Son.</verse>
	<verse from="1 Timothy 4:4-5" version="NAS">For everything created by God is good, and nothing is to be rejected if it is received with gratitude;for it is sanctified by means of the word of God and prayer.</verse>
	<verse from="Luke 9:25" version="NAS">For what is a man profited if he gains the whole world, and loses or forfeits himself ?</verse>
	<verse from="Luke 10:20" version="NAS">Nevertheless do not rejoice in this, that the spirits are subject to you, but rejoice that your names are recorded in heaven.</verse>
	<verse from="Luke 12:10" version="NAS">And everyone who speaks a word against the Son of Man, it will be forgiven him; but he who blasphemes against the Holy Spirit, it will not be forgiven him.</verse>
	<verse from="Luke 12:2" version="NAS">But there is nothing covered up that will not be revealed, and hidden that will not be known.</verse>
	<verse from="Luke 16:10" version="NAS">He who is faithful in a very little thing is faithful also in much ; and he who is unrighteous in a very little thing is unrighteous also in much.</verse>
	<verse from="Luke 18:27" version="NAS">Jesus replied, "What is impossible with men is possible with God."</verse>
	<verse from="Philippians 4:13" version="NAS">I can do all things through Him who strengthens me.</verse>
	<verse from="Philippians 1:6" version="NAS">being confident of this, that he who began a good work in you will carry it on to completion until the day of Christ Jesus.</verse>
	<verse from="Philippians 2:13" version="NAS">for it is God who is at work in you, both to will and to work for His good pleasure.</verse>
	<verse from="Luke 19:10" version="NAS">For the Son of Man has come to seek and to save that which was lost.</verse>
	<verse from="Romans 2:7" version="NAS">To those who by persistence in doing good seek glory, honor and immortality, he will give eternal life.</verse>
	<verse from="James 4:10" version="NAS">umble yourselves in the presence of the Lord, and He will exalt you.</verse>
	<verse from="Hebrews 12:10" version="NAS">For they disciplined us for a short time as seemed best to them, but He disciplines us for our good, so that we may share His holiness.</verse>
	<verse from="1 Corinthians 15:58" version="NAS">Let nothing move you. Always give yourselves fully to the work of the Lord, because you know that your labor in the Lord is not in vain.</verse>
	<verse from="Job 11:16" version="NAS">You will surely forget your trouble, recalling it only as waters gone by.</verse>
	<verse from="John 6:63" version="NAS">It is the Spirit who gives life ; the flesh profits nothing ; the words that I have spoken to you are spirit and are life.</verse>
	<verse from="Acts 4:12" version="NAS">And there is salvation in no one else; for there is no other name under heaven that has been given among men by which we must be saved.</verse>
	<verse from="Acts 5:38" version="NAS">for if this plan or action is of men, it will be overthrown;</verse>
	<verse from="1 Corinthians 1:20" version="NAS">Where is the wise man ? Where is the scribe ? Where is the debater of this age ? Has not God made foolish the wisdom of the world ?</verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 27:14" version="NAS">Wait for the Lord; be strong and take heart and wait for the Lord.</verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 118:1" version="NAS">Give thanks to the LORD, for He is good; For His loving kindness is everlasting.</verse>
	<verse from="Romans 12:2" version="NAS">And do not be conformed to this world, but be transformed by the renewing of your mind, so that you may prove what the will of God is, that which is good and acceptable and perfect.</verse>
	<verse from="1 Corinthians 8:12" version="NAS">And so, by sinning against the brethren and wounding their conscience when it is weak, you sin against Christ.</verse>
	<verse from="1 Corinthians 12:3" version="NAS">Therefore I make known to you that no one speaking by the Spirit of God says, "Jesus is accursed "; and no one can say, "Jesus is Lord," except by the Holy Spirit.</verse>
	<verse from="1 Corinthians 13:2" version="NAS">If I have the gift of prophecy, and know all mysteries and all knowledge ; and if I have all faith, so as to remove mountains, but do not have love, I am nothing.</verse>
	<verse from="1 Corinthians 16:13" version="NAS">Be on the alert, stand firm in the faith, act like men, be strong.</verse>
	<verse from="Ecclesiastes 10:10" version="NAS">If the axe is dull and he does not sharpen its edge, then he must exert more strength. Wisdom has the advantage of giving success.</verse>
	<verse from="Ezekiel 3:18" version="NAS">"When I say to the wicked, 'You will surely die,' and you do not warn him or speak out to warn the wicked from his wicked way that he may live, that wicked man shall die in his iniquity, but his blood I will require at your hand.</verse>
	<verse from="Proverbs 3:27" version="NAS">Do not withhold good from those to whom it is due, When it is in your power to do it.</verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 28:7" version="NAS">The LORD is my strength and my shield; my heart trusts in him, and I am helped. My heart leaps for joy and I will give thanks to him in song.</verse>
	<verse from="Proverbs 24:10" version="NAS">If you falter in times of trouble, how small is your strength!</verse>
	<verse from="Ephesians 4:29" version="NAS">Let no unwholesome word proceed from your mouth, but only such a word as is good for edification according to the need of the moment, so that it will give grace to those who hear.</verse>
	<verse from="Ephesians 5:17" version="NAS">Therefore do not be foolish, but understand what the Lord's will is.</verse>
	<verse from="2 Timothy 2:15" version="NAS">Be diligent to present yourself approved to God as a workman who does not need to be ashamed, accurately handling the word of truth.</verse>
	<verse from="1 Corinthians 10:31" version="NAS">Whether, then, you eat or drink or whatever you do, do all to the glory of God.</verse>
	<verse from="Hebrews 13:5" version="NAS">Keep your lives free from the love of money and be content with what you have, because God has said, "Never will I leave you; never will I forsake you."</verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 69:30-31" version="NAS">I will praise the name of God with song And magnify Him with thanksgiving. And it will please the LORD better than an ox Or a young bull with horns and hoofs.</verse>
	<verse from="Hebrews 12:28" version="NAS">Therefore, since we receive a kingdom which cannot be shaken, let us show gratitude, by which we may offer to God an acceptable service with reverence and awe.</verse>
	<verse from="Isaiah 54:17" version="NAS">"No weapon that is formed against you will prosper ; And every tongue that accuses you in judgment you will condemn. This is the heritage of the servants of the LORD, And their vindication is from Me," declares the LORD.</verse>
	<verse from="Jeremiah 29:11" version="NAS">'For I know the plans that I have for you,' declares the LORD, 'plans for welfare and not for calamity to give you a future and a hope.</verse>
	<verse from="Proverbs 11:25" version="NAS">The generous man will be prosperous, And he who waters will himself be watered.</verse>
	<verse from="Proverbs 28:13" version="NAS">He who conceals his transgressions will not prosper, But he who confesses and forsakes them will find compassion.</verse>
	<verse from="Deuteronomy 29:9" version="NAS">"So keep the words of this covenant to do them, that you may prosper in all that you do.</verse>
	<verse from="Deuteronomy 5:33" version="NAS">"You shall walk in all the way which the LORD your God has commanded you, that you may live and that it may be well with you, and that you may prolong your days in the land which you will possess.</verse>
	<verse from="Ecclesiastes 4:9-10" version="NAS">Two are better than one because they have a good return for their labor. For if either of them falls, the one will lift up his companion. But woe to the one who falls when there is not another to lift him up.</verse>
	<verse from="Psalms 126:5" version="NAS">Those who sow in tears will reap with songs of joy.</verse>
	<verse from="Colossians 3:13" version="NAS">bearing with one another, and forgiving each other, whoever  has a complaint against anyone ; just as the Lord forgave you, so also should you.</verse>
	<verse from="Isaiah 54:2" version="NAS">"Enlarge the place of your tent ; Stretch out the curtains of your dwellings, spare not; Lengthen your cords And strengthen your pegs.</verse>
	<verse from="Ephesians 2:10" version="NAS">For we are His workmanship, created in Christ Jesus for good works, which God prepared beforehand so that we would walk in them.</verse>
	<verse from="Ephesians 3:7" version="NAS">of which I was made a minister, according to the gift of God's grace which was given to me according to the working of His power.</verse>
	<verse from="Ephesians 4:26-27" version="NAS">Be angry, and yet do not sin; do not let the sun go down on your anger, and do not give the devil an opportunity.</verse>
	<verse from="Ephesians 5:8" version="NAS">for you were formerly darkness, but now you are Light in the Lord ; walk as children of Light.</verse>
	<verse from="Ephesians 5:14" version="NAS">For this reason it says, "Awake, sleeper, And arise from the dead, And Christ will shine on you."</verse>
	<verse from="Ephesians 5:17" version="NAS">So then do not be foolish, but understand what the will of the Lord is.</verse>
	<verse from="Ephesians 5:25" version="NAS">Husbands, love your wives, just as Christ also loved the church and gave Himself up for her.</verse>
	<verse from="Ephesians 6:2" version="NAS">Honor your father and mother (which is the first commandment with a promise ), so that it may be well with you, and that you may live long on the earth.</verse>
	<verse from="Ephesians 6:6" version="NAS">Not by way of eyeservice, as men-pleasers, but as slaves of Christ, doing the will of God from the heart.</verse>
	<verse from="Ephesians 6:7" version="NAS">With good will render service, as to the Lord, and not to men.</verse>
	<verse from="Romans 1:20" version="NAS">For since the creation of the world His invisible attributes, His eternal power and divine nature, have been clearly seen, being understood through what has been made, so that they are without excuse.</verse>
	<verse from="Romans 2:29" version="NAS">But he is a Jew who is one inwardly ; and circumcision is that which is of the heart, by the Spirit, not by the letter.</verse>
	<verse from="Romans 3:20" version="NAS"> because by the works of the Law no flesh will be justified in His sight ; for through the Law comes the knowledge of sin.</verse>
	<verse from="Romans 4:25" version="NAS"> He who was delivered over because of our transgressions, and was raised because of our justification.</verse>
	<verse from="Romans 6:3" version="NAS"> Or do you not know that all of us who have been baptized into Christ Jesus have been baptized into His death ?</verse>
	<verse from="Romans 6:23" version="NAS">For the wages of sin is death, but the free gift of God is eternal life in Christ Jesus our Lord.</verse>
	<verse from="Romans 7:18" version="NAS">For I know that nothing good dwells in me, that is, in my flesh ; for the willing is present in me, but the doing of the good is not.</verse>
	<verse from="Romans 8:2" version="NAS">For the law of the Spirit of life in Christ Jesus has set you free from the law of sin and of death.</verse>
	<verse from="Romans 8:6" version="NAS">For the mind set on the flesh is death, but the mind set on the Spirit is life and peace.</verse>
	<verse from="Romans 9:8" version="NAS">That is, it is not the children of the flesh who are children of God, but the children of the promise are regarded as descendants. </verse>
	<verse from="Romans 10:13" version="NAS">for "Whoever will call on the name of the Lord will be saved."  </verse>
	<verse from="Romans 10:9" version="NAS"> that if you confess with your mouth Jesus as Lord, and believe in your heart that God raised Him from the dead, you will be saved ;  </verse>
	<verse from="Romans 11:29" version="NAS">for the gifts and the calling of God are irrevocable.</verse>
	<verse from="Romans 12:1" version="NAS">I beseech you therefore, brethren, by the mercies of God, to present your bodies a living sacrifice, holy, acceptable to God, [which is] your spiritual service.</verse>
	<verse from="Romans 12:11" version="NAS">in diligence not slothful; fervent in spirit; serving the Lord.</verse>
	<verse from="Romans 12:12" version="NAS">rejoicing in hope; patient in tribulation; continuing stedfastly in prayer;</verse>
	<verse from="Romans 13:8" version="NAS">Owe nothing to anyone except to love one another ; for he who loves his neighbor has fulfilled the law. </verse>
	<verse from="Romans 13:7" version="NAS">Render to all what is due them: tax to whom tax is due; custom to whom custom ; fear to whom fear ; honor to whom honor. </verse>
	<verse from="Romans 14:8" version="NAS">For if we live, we live for the Lord, or if we die, we die for the Lord; therefore whether we live or die, we are the Lord's.</verse>
</verses>
